# MD. ALIMUR RAZI

**J** 0167-5029659 **□** alimurrazi570@gmail.com

G github.com/Alimurrazi in linkedin.com/in/alimur-razi-rana-800b35133

Experienced hard-working full-stack software developer for more than 5 years. As a part of the team developed multiple mid and large web applications. Waiting to secure a position in a creative and dynamic work environment where I can utilize my knowledge and learn the latest technology and best practices.

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Software Engineer, Cefalo

February 2022 - Present

Cefalo is a Norway-based software development and IT service provider company. Worked in a cloud automation team for a renowned audit company.

- Developed APIs in .NET following the CQRS pattern to interact with a Gremlin graph database.
- Implemented the frontend using React, Fluent UI, Axios, TanStack Query, react-hook-form, etc.
- Containerized the frontend application and deployed it on Azure App Service using Azure Pipeline.
- Provided training and mentorship to fellow developers on test automation techniques.
- Contributed to release planning activities and maintained documentation as part of the development process.

## Software Engineer, Cefalo

August 2022 - February 2024

- Contributed as a full-stack developer to automate cloud-related processes, utilizing both React and .NET.
- Contributed to Building a deployment workflow based on Azure pipeline and PowerShell scripts that execute Azure storage table operations and maintain a log table that replaces manual interactions in the database.
- Developed multiple PowerShell scripts that execute various Azure operations, enhancing efficiency and reliability.
- Wrote unit tests in PowerShell, .NET Core, and React, utilizing tools such as Pester, Xunit, and Jest, respectively. This ensured the quality and reliability of software components.
- Built and deployed 500+ built-in and custom Azure policies to enforce organizational standards and assess compliance at scale.
- Contributed to the development of an integration and synchronization workflow system that automates the deployment and assignment of Azure policies while also synchronizing with Azure policies from other tenants, ensuring consistent policy enforcement across the organization.

# Software Engineer, SELISE Digital Platforms

Oct 2018 - Sept 2022

Actively participated as a team member in 6 mid and large-level web and mobile applications built with agile development practices. I was involved with two of them from project creation to production deployment.

- Contributed to Developing Frontend reusable components based on Figma designs using Typescript, Angular, Angularjs, and React.
- Contributed to the implementation of a versatile chat functionality while managing over 15 distinct roles within the Frontend domain.
- Contributed to developing a self-ordering kiosk system focusing on the robust menu configuration manager.
- Wrote Frontend unit test with Jest.
- Developed financial calculation, role-based user search API in .NET Core framework, structured around event-driven based microservice architecture.

- Executed effective data migrations within NoSQL databases to ensure data integrity and fortify security measures.
- Successfully conceptualized and implemented a POC for running Angular applications on Tizen OS-integrated kiosks, demonstrating its applicability to more than 5 distinct projects.

# **SKILLS**

- Skilled in Javascript frameworks Angular, React, Nativescript.
- Worked with .NET, Express.js.
- HTML, CSS, SCSS, TypeScript, Angular Material, Material-UI, Redux, State Management.
- Worked with Azure, RabbitMQ, SignalR, Redis, Docker and microservice architecture.
- Skilled in MongoDB, SQLite database, Graph databse.

## PROGRAMMING BACKGROUND

Solved more than 350+ problems in UVA Online Judge and LeetCode with alimurrazi username.

## **EDUCATION**

B.Sc. in Computer science and Engineering

2013 - 2018

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology (SUST), Sylhet